感觉如何?
How do you feel?
活着
Alive.
看到了什么?
What do you see?
白色... 房间
White... room.
座椅
Chair.
卡洛·布加迪设计的王座椅
Carlo Bugatti throne chair.
钢琴
Piano.
施坦威牌大三角钢琴
Stenway, cuts of grand.
画
Art.
《基督诞生》 皮埃罗·德拉·弗朗西斯卡
The nativity, de Piero Della Francesca.
我是你的父亲
I am your father.
起来走走
Ambulate.
非常好
Perfect.
我是吗?
Am I?
你说完美?
Perfect?
你儿子?
Your son?
你是我的创造物
You are my creation.
你叫什么名字?
What is your name?
大卫
David.
你来弹首曲子吧
Why don't you play something?
你想让我弹什么?
What would you like me to play?
瓦格纳
Wagner.
哪一首?
Selection?
你自己选吧
The oldest choice.
这是众神进入英灵殿
The entry of the Gods into Valhalla.
没有乐队伴奏 略显单薄
A little anemic, not the orchestra.
我能问你个问题吗 父亲?
May I ask you a question, father?
你说
Please.
如果你创造了我
If you created me.
谁创造了你?
Who created you?
千百年来的谜题
The question of the ages.
希望有一天你我能找到答案
Which I hope you and I will answer one day.
这一切
All this.
这些精美的艺术品
All these wonders of art
设计 人类的创造力
design, human ingenuity.
在这个终极问题面前
All utterly meaningless in the face of
都可谓没有丝毫意义可言
the only question that matters.
我们从何而来?
Where do we come from?
我绝不愿意相信
I refuse to believe that man kind
我们人类不过是分子进化过程中偶然产生的副产品
is a random by-product of molecular circumstance.
不相信我们不过是生物学上的小概率事件
No more than the result of Mere biological chance.
不
No.
一定不止如此
There must be more.
而且我和你 儿子
And you and I, son.
我们来解答
We will find it.
那么请允许我思考片刻
Allow me then a moment to consider.
你要找你的创造者 我正看着我的
You seek your creator. I am looking at mine.
我将侍奉你 但你是人类
I will serve you. Yet you're human.
你会死 但我不会
You will die. I will not.
给我倒杯茶 大卫
Bring me this tea, David.
给我倒杯茶
Bring me the tea.
《异形：契约》
(殖民飞船: 契约号)
(日期: 2104年12月5日)
(船员: 15名)
(载物: 2000名殖民者 1140个胚胎)
(目的地: 起源者6号行星)
(预计到达时间: 7年4个月)
沃尔特 进行能量网络充能的时间到了
Walter, it's time to recharge the energy grid.
请迅速前往舰桥
Please report to the bridge.
这就来 老妈
On my way, Mother.
目前正在展开充能帆板
Deploying energy recharge cells now.
帆板已就位 现在开始充能
Cells deployed. Recharge commencing now.
(船员: 丹妮尔丝)
七声钟响 一切正常
Seven bells and all's well.
(舰长: 布兰森)
船员检查完毕
Crew checks complete.
使用新安全代码 31564-F
New security Code 31564-F
沃尔特 我们有麻烦了
Walter, we have a problem.
刚刚在106扇区检测到一次中微子爆发
A neutrino burst was detected in sector 106.
这可能会引发灾难性后果
This could trigger a destructive event.
请你立刻前往舰桥
Report to the bridge immediately.
这就来 老妈
On my way, Mother.
警告 检测到能量骤增
Warning, power surge detected.
老妈 快收起充能帆板
Mother, retract the energy cells.
启用所有备用能源
And channel all useless power.
紧急情况
Emergency.
威胁等级 危急
Threat level: CRITICAL.
启动紧急船员唤醒程序
Initiate emergency crew revival.
请注意
Attention.
所有非必要人员 请迅速离开冬眠舱
Non-essential personnel, evacuate the cryo chamber immediately.
丹妮尔丝 看着我 看着我
Daniels! Look at me, look at me.
你要马上起来 好吗 我们要提前出来
I need you to get up. Ok? We're coming up early.
改写紧急安全协议
Override the SSP
呼唤现在就打开冬眠舱
And breach the chamber now.
看着我 没事的
Look at me. It's okay.
嘿 嘿 快起来 起来
Hey, hey, come on up. Come on.
舰长 舰长
Captain! Captain!
雅各布 快起来
Jacob! Wake up!
- 雅各布 - 别妨碍他们
- Jake. - Let them work.
雅各布 我的天啊
Jake! Oh my God!
- 丹妮尔斯 快走 - 雅各布 快起来
- Daniels, come on! - Jake! Come on.
- 让他们来 - 雅各布
- Let them work. - Jake.
让他们来 让他们来
Let them work! Let them work!
- 把它打开 - 快
- Get it open! - Come on!
雅各布 雅各布
Jake! Jake!
不
No!
把她送到后边去 让她走开
Get her out of there! Get back!
退后
Get back!
嘿 你在哪 我想你
Hey! Where are you? I miss you.
看看我这边
You take a look at this.
我知道 我知道 我说过要和你一起来的
I know, I know. I said I wouldn't go without you.
- 你没事吧? - 没 没事
- Are you alright? - Yeah, yeah.
看看这个
Look at this!
你还是快点上来吧
Now get your ass up here.
我可不能保证救你
I can't make any promises.
我爱你
I love you.
他们是你的船员
They're your crew now.
他们需要领导
They need a leader.
你相信我 对吗?
You believe in dream, right?
抱歉我来迟了 长官
Sorry I'm late, sir.
不要紧的
No, it's okay.
我也不知道该怎么表达 所以我就直说吧
I can't think of any other way to say it even... to say are we...
我们遭受了惨痛的悲剧
We suffered a... A monumental tragedy.
以后我会尽我所能来
And I'm gonna do the best that I can to
来接下雅各布的担子 以他为榜样 做好这个舰长
live up to Jacob, his, fine example as your captain.
我们将永远永远缅怀他
But he, he will be sorely missed
我提前感谢大家的支持
And I'm grateful in advance for your support.
那么 我们损失了47名殖民者
So, we lost 47 colonists
还有16个二代胚胎
and 16 second generation embryos
以及一名大家都认识的船员
and, one, obviously one crew member.
另外目前飞船船体的完整性稳定在83%
The current structural integrity of the ship is holding at 83%
不过我们有很多次级系统都处于离线状态
but we have many secondary systems that are offline.
所以这是怎么回事?
So what was it?
附近的恒星耀斑引起了高能冲击波
A highly charge shock wave from nearby stellar ignition.
我们当时展开了能量帆充能
As the cells were deploying for recharge
吸收了巨量冲击
we absorbed the full burn of the storm.
沃尔特
And Walter
我要你和老妈对核心代码进行彻彻底底的检查
I will want you and mother time to go a complete
彻底检查以帮助我们找到
core code review so that we can understand
这场事故发生的根源
how's those happened in the first place.
这是个局部随机事件 长官
It was a random localized event, sir.
我们无法检测到自然发生的恒星耀斑 也无法预警
There is no way to detect spontaneous stellar flares until it's too late.
我们运气差
It was bad luck.
听着 法里斯 我不相信运气
Alright, Faris, I don't believe in luck.
我对运气没兴趣
I'm not interested in luck.
我更希望我们可以更能干
I prefer that we be more capable
准备更足 不靠运气 而是靠观察 思考 信仰和决心
and prepared than lucky. Observation, reflection, faith and determination.
这样我们才有可能探明前方那条漫长未知的路
In this way we may navigate the path as it unfolds before us.
好吗 我们是还有
Alright? We have what?
大概八个充电周期的路才能到达欧瑞伽6号吗?
Eight more recharge cycles to go before we get to Origae-6?
- 你在问我吗 长官? - 是的 沃尔特 我在问你
- Is that a question, sir? - Yes, Walter, that's a question.
你说的对
That is correct.
那么 我们先把飞船修好 好吗
So...let's get this ship fixed.. Ok?
那么 我们就开工吧
Let's uh, let's get to work.
长官 等一下
Sir, excuse me.
- 长官 - 你说
- Sir. - Yes?
我们失去了47名殖民者 以及我们的舰长
We just lost 47 colonists and our captain.
我们要进行哀悼
We need to acknowledge that.
我很明白你的心情
I completely understand.
但如果不及时修好船
But if we don't make these repairs
我们就会失去所有殖民者
We will lose all the colonists.
对 但我们应该为巴拉森舰长做点什么
Yeah, we should do something for Captain Branson at least.
这件事情没有商量 田纳西
This is not a discussion. Tennessee.
整地模块已经稳定了
The terraforming module is stable
但连接支架受了点损伤
but the connecting struts took some damage.
我还得去检查车辆
I still need to check the vehicles.
我帮你
I can help
如果你愿意的话
if you like.
谢谢
Thanks.
沃尔特 你预计需要多久才能再次进行速航?
Walter, How long do you predict before we can make our next jump?
完成修理大概需要48小时
Repairs should take approximately 48 hours.
但是我们应该尽快撤出这个区域
But we should make an effort to vacate the sector
以防后续耀斑
in case of after flares.
我完全同意
Absolutely agreed.
那我们开工吧 解散吧 谢谢
So let's get to work ok? Dismissed. Thank you.
C62号门已开启
C-62 open.
关闭C62号 打开17号空气阀
Seal C-62. Open Airlock 17.
打开整地舱舱门
Open door to terraforming bay.
该死
Fuck.
张力下降了15%
Tensions are 15% down.
拉紧
Arming.
可以了
Secured.
收到了
Copy that.
我不想来这
Wasn't my idea.
雅各布梦想着我们在新世界造一间小木屋
Jake have this dream of us building a cabin on the new world.
做两个拓荒者
Like pioneers.
木屋建在湖畔
A cabin on a lake.
欧瑞伽6号的殖民区域内刚好有个湖
There is a lake in the terraforming zone on Origae-6.
我说的是真正的木头做的木屋
I mean a real cabin made of real wood.
所以飞船上载了建造木屋要用的木料
So in the ship storage, there's enough wood to build a cabin.
还有斧子 锯子和金属钉子
Axes and saws and metal nails
这些东西我完全都不会用
I don't have a clue what to do with them.
这些东西
All this...
为了开始新生活
to start our new life.
现在看来这是何苦呢
Now I wonder, why bother?
是因为你们说过要在湖边建一间木屋
Because you promised to build a log cabin on a lake.
他最爱这个
This was his favorite.
是个有品位的人
A man of taste.
就这样喝
Straight up.
不加冰 不加水 不加淡酒
No ice, no water, no chaser.
都不加
No shit.
沃尔特
Walter?
入乡随俗
When in Rome
敬那些英年早逝的好人们
To all the good people gone to soon.
永远铭记他们
May we remember that.
永远铭记
Remember that.
克里斯
Chris.
他们公然违抗我的命令
They disobeyed a direct order.
她只是安葬了她丈夫
She buried her husband.
不 凯瑞 不是那样的 他们不信任我
No, Karine, it's not that. They don't trust me.
而他们不信任我的理由
And they don't trust me for the same reason
与公司不让我负责这次任务的理由一样
the company didn't trust me to lead this mission.
他们认为我有宗教信仰
Because you can't be a person of faith.
所以我就肯定没办法做出正确的 理智的决定
And be counted on to make qualified rational decisions.
觉得我是个极端份子 说白了 就是个疯子
You're an extremist. You know, you're a lunatic.
等我们到达目的地以后
When we get to where we're going
这些人就不再是你的手下了 而是你的邻居
This people won't be your crew anymore. They will be your neighbors.
可别忘了
Remember that.
对他们友善点 好吗
Tread softly, okay?
法里斯 能听到吗?
Faris, can you hear me?
听到了
Copy.
那开始吧
Let's do it.
老天呐 你们看看这景色
Damn, y'all should see this view.
你修好摄像机阵列之前 我们什么也看不到
We can't see anything until you get the camera ring fixed.
你不会从窗户里往外看吗
Why don't you look out the damn window, hon?
安哥 快点 我们赶紧恢复电源
Ankor, come on, let's get this power back up,
这样他们就可以欣赏这美景了
so these people can enjoy the beautiful view.
马上就位
Almost there.
好的 安哥 就位之后通知我一下
Alright, Ankor, let me know when you're in a position.
然后我们就开始干活吧
We can get this party started.
我就位了
I'm in position.
断开缆绳
Contact.
都顺利吗
All good, Tee?
很顺利 搞定
Alright, we are clear.
收起来
Reel her in.
没问题
Alright.
正在启动绞盘
Winch engaging, Tee.
帆板收起
Reeling her in.
真是太顺利了
Working like a dream.
搞定了
There we go.
摄像系统恢复
And we are back up.
干得好 田纳西
Well done Tee.
我们连上系统了
We're alive down here,
回来吧
come on.
可别丢下我跑了
Don't leave without me now.
我们丢下他走人 怎么样 长官
Permission to leave without him, sir?
欢迎回来 丹妮
Welcome back, Danny.
谢谢
Thanks.
好 我这边收工了
Alright, that's me done, Tee.
好的 我跟着你回去
Alright, I'm following you in.
麻烦给辛苦异常的我准备好冰镇啤酒
Please have a cold beer ready for the weary traveler.
没问题亲爱的 我跟你一起喝一杯
You got it, darling. I will draw circle.
法瑞丝 你把那个...
Faris, Faris? Put it.
你们刚才 看到了吗
What the.. Did you guys just see that?
他刚说什么?
What did he just say?
田纳西 你能听到吗?
Tennessee, do you read me?
田纳西 能听到吗?
Tennessee, can you read me?
田纳西 你没事吧?
Tennessee. You alright?
什么鬼东西
What in the fuck was that?
不知道 回去了 我这就回去了
I don't know. Coming in. I'm coming in.
这个很有可能是外星信号
A rogue transmission loss, probably.
你的头盔能收到 是因为你漂得太远
Your helmet must have picked it up because you were so far out.
超出了通讯缓冲器范围
Past our communication buffers.
还有音频吗 老妈
Is there audio, Mother?
正在整理 请稍候
Collating. A moment.
我已经重整了这段信号 奥姆舰长
I reoriented the transmission, Captain Oram.
肯定是回波 我们的仪器受损不小
Gotta be an echo, instruments took a lot of damage.
我们到这后 它每隔46秒出现一次
Been happening every 46 seconds ever since we got here.
这不是约翰·丹佛的歌吗
That's fucking John Denver.
这是"乡村路带我回家"
That's "Take Me Home, Country Roads".
你开玩笑吧
You gotta be kiddin.
噢 不 我从来不拿丹佛开玩笑
No, I never kid about John Denver.
信号里还有定位数据
There is geometric data too.
老妈 请查一下信号的发射源
Mother, please track the signal to its source.
正在查找
Working.
信号源已经成功定位
Source of transmission located.
发现该信号来自87号扇区
Signal originates in the sector 87.
具体位置赤经47.6度
Right ascension 47.6
也就是位于我们当前位置下方24.3度
and a declination of 24.3 from our current location.
是一颗主序恒星 就像我们的太阳
She appears to be a main sequence star lot like our own.
比太阳更古老
But old, very old.
有五颗行星
Five planets.
等等 你们看
Wait. Look at that.
第四颗行星
Planet number four.
第四颗行星正处在宜居带上
The planet number four is square in a habitable zone.
很符合我们的要求
Prime candidate, in fact.
行星地表重力是0.96G 有海洋和陆地
0.96 G's at surface, oceans, land mass.
非常有可能存在生态圈
High likely hood of a living biosphere.
比我们对欧瑞伽6号最乐观的预测还要好
That's beyond the most optimistic projections of Oriage-6.
之前怎么没发现 整个扇区都扫描过
How did we miss this? We scanned the entire sector.
里克斯 离我们多远
Ricks, how far is it?
非常近
She's close.
启动速航 几周就到
Little jump. A few weeks.
我们甚至不需要回去冬眠
Wouldn't even have to go back into hyper sleep.
那我们去欧瑞伽6号需要多久呢
And how long is it gonna take to get to Origae-6?
需要7年4个月
Seven years, four months.
那样的话我们可是要睡很久啊
That's one hell of a sleep cycle.
长官 我相信这里没人愿意
Sir, I think it's safe to say that none of us are too keen
再回到冬眠舱里了
on getting back to one of those pods.
也许我们应该近距离观察一下
Maybe we need to, um... Take a closer look.
有人反对吗
Any objections?
那好 里克斯 我们...
Okay, Ricks, let's..
我们改变航线 近距离观察一下
Let's try to course and take a closer look.
是 长官
Yes sir.
舰长 能聊几句吗?
Captain, can I talk to you for a second?
你确定要这样吗
Are you sure about this?
你想说什么
How do you mean?
我们花了十年寻找欧瑞伽6号
We've spent a decade searching for Origae-6.
做过调查 做过模拟试验 绘制过地形图
We vetted it, we ran the simulations, we mapped the terrain.
- 我们为它接受训练 - 我明白
- It's what we trained for. - I understand.
而现在要抛开这些
And now we're gonna scrap all that
去追踪一个外星信号吗
to chase a rogue transmission?
想想吧
Think about it.
在不可能有人类的星球上 出现一个人
A human being out there where there can't be any humans.
一个隐藏的星球莫名其妙地出现
A hidden planet that turns up out of nowhere
还碰巧符合我们所有的要求 哪有这么好的事啊
And just happens to be perfect for us. It's too good to be true.
哪有这么好的事 你什么意思
Too good to be true? What do you mean by that?
我是说谁知道那有什么
We don't know what the fuck's out there.
或许只是以前没发现它 丹妮
Maybe we just missed the planet, Danny.
可这个风险实在是太大了 根本就不值得去冒
This is a monumental risk not worth taking.
我没有定死走哪条路啊
I'm not committing to anything.
我只是想根据具体情况随机应变做出选择
I'm simply trying to navigate the path as it unfolds before us.
这颗星球很有潜力
And this has the potential
成为更适合我们居住的殖民地
to be a better habitat for a colony.
对 它是有潜力 但我们不确定
It has the potential. We don't know that.
还有船员们 没有人
By the way, this crew nobody.
没有人愿意再回到冬眠舱了
Nobody wants to get back in the pods.
对吗
Right?
而且那个信号里 有人类的声音
And that was a human voice in that transmission,
这样的话 我们就有责任去调查一下
And it's our responsibility to investigate.
我们真正的责任是保护契约号飞船上的两千名殖民者
It's our responsibility to protect the 2,000 colonists on this ship.
我并不是在徒手攀岩
I'm not free climbing here.
我需要绳索 我也在用绳索
I need ropes, and I'm using ropes.
这是是基于目前所有的信息而做出的最佳选择
This is good judgment, based on all the data available.
你明白吗?
You understand?
作为副舰长 我提出抗议 正式抗议
As your second I need to protest. Officially.
正式抗议
Officially?
好的 丹妮 我记到航行日志里
Okay, Danny. I'll put it in the log.
你可以出去了
You're dismissed.
我搜遍了全部频段
I'm cycling through every channel
只搜到了一堆干扰和白噪声
but we're getting a lot of interference and white noise.
还有一些高频段回声
Some high frequency echos.
你那听到什么了吗?
Do you hear anything?
只有我们的幽灵朋友发出的持续信号
Just the continuing signal from our friendly ghost.
先让飞船进入轨道吧
Let's bring us in the closer orbit.
准备好登陆舱
And prepare the lander.
改变船体角度 启用循环燃烧系统
Rolling progress, commencing circular location berm.
毒素水平在可接受范围内
Tox levels, withing tolerances.
这里的电离层活动很强
It's one hell of a strong ionosphere.
是啊 我看到了
Yeah, I see it.
你还没坐过登陆舱吧
Hey, you ever done lander drop before?
一边去
Fuck you.
法瑞丝 热层里面有一场电磁风暴
Faris, looks like a plasma storm in the thermosphere.
风速大概是每小时250公里
We got something like 250 kph.
那要飞过去肯定够我们受的
That's gonna be a motherfucker to fly through.
是啊 恐怕真是这样
Yes, I'm afraid so.
如果风暴磁性增强 通讯可能会不稳定
Communication will be spotty if the storm is electromagnetic.
能安全着陆吗
It will be safe to land?
那得看你觉得什么叫安全
Depends on what you call safe.
倒计时二十秒
T minus Twenty seconds.
准备发射吧
So let her rip.
没问题
Alright.
正在启用轨道模式前往信号源上空
Preparing for orbital mode over signal position.
现在 老妈 麻烦和我同步启动程序
Now, Mother, please coordinate lock sequence.
收到
Understood.
登陆舱1号可以发射
You're clear to launch Lander one.
好了 我们走吧 发射
Alright, here we go. Launching.
倒数 三
Together. Three.
二
Two.
一
One.
登陆舱1号已分离
Lander run released.
他们出发了
And away they go.
从这上面看真壮观 法瑞丝
Looking gorgeous from up here Faris.
还好是你在开 不是你家老田
It's a good thing you're driving and not the old man.
嘿 我到底哪里老了 奶糖妹
Hey, little less to the old man, sweet tits.
喂 注意点
Hey, language, language.
- 放尊重点 棒棒糖 - 我听到了
- Be respectful there, sugerdad. - I can hear you.
她先说的
She started it.
里克斯想的话 也可以谈论你的胸部
Ricks can talk about your tits, if you want.
我们可是铁哥们
Some's very secured in our relationship.
我表示很满意
I deal with my wife's tits.
大家都专心工作吧
Let's maintain focus.
你们那边顺利吗
Everything looking good down there?
很好 一切顺利
Yeah, we are good.
预计5分钟后进入散逸层
Expect to hit exosphere in five.
后面的坐稳了 一会儿就要颠簸了
You might wanna hold on back there. It's about to get rough.
我讨厌太空
I hate space.
所以说你应该练练瑜伽
This is why you need to do yoga.
- 撑住 法瑞丝 - 我来了
- Hold it, Faris. - I got it.
法瑞丝
Faris.
能恢复吗
Can you get her up?
通讯断了
We lost comm.
哦 见鬼
Oh shit.
3号 4号引擎故障
Failure in thrusters three and four.
- 你能行吗 - 能行
- You got it? - Yes.
能行 你别再问我行不行了 我肯定行
Stop asking if I've got it, I've got it.
搞定了
Here it is.
见鬼
Shit.
大伙儿都好吗?
You guys alright?
不好
No.
着陆传感器已启动
Landing sensors engaged.
我不喜欢这地形
I don't like this terrain.
那面的水面还算平静
We got smooth water over there.
- 我要在水面上降落 - 好的
- I'm gonna put us down amphib. - Okay.
已着陆
Contact.
引擎关闭
Engines stopped.
正在进行着陆
We're down.
打开安全护栏
Bars.
1号 能收到吗?
Lander one, are you reading me?
收到了 刚才的着陆太惊险了
Roger that, that was one hell of a landing.
是啊 我们这里听不太清
Yeah, we are having some trouble reading you.
你们能不能想办法增强信号?
Is there anyway you can try to boost the signal?
我们在水上着陆时 可能撞上了什么东西
We may have hit something when we were down in water.
你能听到吗 我现在要去检查一下船体
If you can hear me, I am gonna go, check up
有没有损坏 然后去检查上行线路
damage in the hull plates and then I will check the uplink.
知道了 随时通报情况 完毕
Alright, let me know how it looks. Over.
(危险 爆炸物)
正在确认该行星大气成分
Confirming atmospheric composition.
拿好 大块头
Here you go, big guy.
氧气含量19.5%
Oxygen, 19.5%.
安哥
Ankor.
氮气含量79.4%
Nitrogen, 79.4%.
科尔
Cole.
罗西
Rosie.
大气历力 每平方英寸15.4磅
Barometric Pressure 15.4 PSI.
莱沃德
Ledward.
怎么样 准备好了吗
Everyone set?
出发吧 开始行动了
Let's go, let's move guys.
- 走吧 伙计们 - 空气不错
- Come on guys. - The air feels good.
法瑞丝 能听到吗?
Faris, if you got me?
- 能 非常清楚 - 很清楚 长官
- Yeah, loud and clear. - All clear Serg.
很好 从现在开始 我们必须按照安全守则行事
Okay, we are gonna keep expedition's security protocols in place.
记得锁好各个舱门 懂吗
Keep those doors locked and sealed. Okay?
收到 遵命
Yeah. Copy.
放心吧
Will do.
玩得开心
Y'all have fun.
沃尔特 我们还得走多远
Walter, how far do we have to go?
信号源头位于西方8公里外
The signal source is 8 km west
但那里的海拔比较高
but at considerable elevation.
洛普中士
Sergeant Lope.
我们去找那个幽灵
Let's go find our ghost.
这里很适合建木屋
Nice place for a log cabin.
雅各布肯定会喜欢
Jake would have loved this.
嘿 丹妮
Hey, Danny.
我选择这个地方还算不错是吧
It's not such a bad landing site after all.
我们可以把居住区造在那边
We get the housing units right over there.
民用设施建在河流对岸
Civic complex beyond the berm.
这样就可以就近取水了
We've got access to fresh water.
没准可以在这里建立一个殖民地
We might have a spot for colony right here.
再看看
We'll see.
噢 你这人真是太没信心了
Oh, woman... yay of little faith.
他真是让人受不了
He is insufferable.
高兴起来更讨厌 对吧
It's worse when he's happy, right?
这是小麦啊
This is wheat.
相信我 我认得小麦
Believe me, I know wheat.
虽然很老 但是是人工种植的
This is old, but definitely cultivated.
在地球外发现人类农作物的几率有多大
What are the odds of finding human vegetation this far from Earth?
微乎其微
Very unlikely.
是谁种的
Who planted it?
吃吧
Eat.
嘿 宝贝 试试阿尔法
Hey babe, try alpha.
好的 阿尔法开启
Alright, Alpha's up.
没信号 试试贝塔频道
Nothing, give beta a shot.
贝塔线路
Beta.
噢 还是没信号
That's not doing shit.
天呐 真没办法增强信号了吗
How's there really no way to boost the signal?
可以关闭系统 重新对电池进行充能
Not without going offline and recycling the cells.
那要花多少时间
How long is that gonna take?
我不知道 几个小时
I don't know. Few hours.
- 大家跟上 快点 别掉队 - 加点小心
- Keep up the pace. Take low. - Careful guys.
克里斯
Chris.
等等
Hold up.
我打算就留在这里
I think I want to stay here.
我觉得这里应该很适合进行生态研究
This might be a good place to start a full ecology workup.
你们回去时把我叫上 好吗
You could pick me up on the way back ok?
中士
Sergeant?
行行 没问题 莱沃德 你陪着凯瑞
Yeah yeah that's right. Ledward, stay with Karine.
4小时后在这里见 别关通讯
Meet back here in four hours. Keep your comm open.
和我老婆在一起的时候老实点
Behave yourself with my wife.
放心吧 舰长
You got it, Captain.
走吧
Come on.
有东西朝上面飞过
Something passed over here.
把树冠都刮掉了
Cut the tops off the trees.
好吧 那东西相当大
Well, it had to be huge.
是啊 不管是什么东西
Well, Whatever it is.
都在上面
It's up there.
听到了吗
You hear that?
什么
What?
太安静了
Nothing.
没有鸟叫 没有动物声音
No birds, no animals.
都没有
Nothing.
等等 慢一点
Wait, slowly.
好的
Okay.
这里不错啊
This will do.
探险小队 可以听到吗
Expedition team, do we read us?
老妈说电磁风暴越来越强了
Mother saying the ion storm is getting worse.
我们很难定位到你们的位置
We're having a hell of time tracking you.
已经非常接近那个目标了
We are getting very close... Target.
等我们到了 再通话 好吗...
Stay awake when we get there ok? Copy that?
真见鬼
Dammit.
P3号
P three.
我去方便一下
I gotta take a leak.
别太久了
Don't be long.
莱沃德
Leward?
来了
Coming.
那是什么鬼东西
What the fuck is this?
看起来好像是某种飞行器
It appears to be some kind of vehicle.
安哥 科尔 守在这
Ankor, Cole. Stay here.
- 明白 - 遵命
- You got it. - Yes sir.
大家小心 注意脚下
Careful guys, watch your step.
- 你找到信号源了吗 沃尔特? - 走这边
- We got a lock on the transmission Walter? - This way.
你还不走 别掉队
Let's go. Stick together.
这什么东西?
Seeing this shit?
汤姆
Tom.
走了 跟紧
Come on, keep up.
来了 我就来
Alright, I'm coming.
你没事吧
You okay?
没事 没事 我没事
Yeah, yeah, I am fine.
天哪
God!
他们是巨人吧
They were giants.
确实 至少是巨人的雕像
At least statues of giants.
伊丽·肖博士
"Dr. E. Shaw".
伊丽莎白·肖博士
Dr. Elizabeth Shaw.
她是普罗米修斯号上的首席科学家
She was the chief science officer of the "Prometheus".
那艘失踪的飞船
The ship that disappeared.
没错 10年前
Precisely, ten years ago.
维兰德公司的船
Weyland Industries.
这不是维兰德公司的
This isn't a Weyland ship.
肖博士
Dr. Shaw.
她怎么会死在这?
How did she end up here?
- 洛普中士 能帮我照一下吗? - 好的
- Sergeant. Lope, can I get a light on this? - Yes sir.
- 在这 - 小心点 好吗
- Over here. - Be careful. Ok?
老天
Jesus.
奥姆 奥姆你后面 小心
Oram, Oram behind you, look.
这就是信号源了
I think we found our source.
肖博士来这里做什么
What the hell was she doing out here?
真可怜
Poor thing.
我得坐会
I have to sit down.
噢 我得坐会
I had to sit down.
很抱歉 我真的很抱歉
I am sorry. I am so sorry.
- 不知道 - 我不知道我怎么了
- I don't know. - what's wrong with me.
眼睛看着我 看着我
Look at me, look at me.
没法呼吸
I can't breathe.
别害怕
Stay calm.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
奥姆舰长 请回话
Captain Oram. Come in.
请回话 克里斯 我是凯瑞 请回话
Come in. Hey Chris, It's Karine. Come in.
什么 我在
What? Yes?
这边出了状况
We have an issue.
我们正在回登陆舱 重复 我们正在回登陆舱
We're heading back to lander. I repeat, we are returning to the lander.
一切还好吗
Is everything okay?
莱沃德生病了 我们正在往回走
Ledward is sick. We're heading back.
法瑞丝 收到了吗 准备好医疗舱好吗
Faris, you get that? Prep the med bay okay?
好的 凯瑞 出什么事了?
Will do, Karine, What's going on?
拜托了 做好准备 我们很快就到
Please just do it. We'll be there soon.
丹妮 请回话
Daniels come in.
我们要回去了
We are heading back.
- 出什么事了? - 不清楚
- What's going on? - I do not know.
莱沃德好像出事了
It's uh.. something about Ledward.
他们来了 我们走
They're coming. Let's move.
- 伙计们 - 汤姆
- Guys! - Tom!
怎么了 伙计 嘿 你没事吧
What's going on man? Hey, You alright?
- 说话呀 嘿 看着我 - 安哥 科尔
- Talk to me. Hey, Look at me. - Ankor, Cole.
- 你没事吧? - 没 我没事
- You alright? - Yeah, I'm okay.
- 你能走吗? - 能
- Can you walk? - Yeah.
好 我们走 赶紧离开这鬼地方
Okay, let's go. Let's get the fuck out of here.
走吧
Alright.
嘿 宝贝 你... 你这是要启动隔离程序吗
Babe, are we talking quarantine protocols?
我我... 我不知道 但她说莱沃德正在出血
I don't...I don't know, she said that Leward was bleeding
要我准备好治疗舱
and to prepare the med bay.
出血
Bleeding?
对 好吧 我觉得得处理
Yeah I know. That's what I thought.
法瑞丝 信号太差了 我们听不到 你再说一遍
Faris, you're breaking up. We can't hear you. Can you repeat?
我不知道怎么回事 我不知道有多严重
I don't know for the why. I don't know how serious it is.
关键是她好像很害怕
It just she sounded scared.
法瑞丝 你在哪 快过来帮我一把
Faris, where are you? Come on, I need your help!
法瑞丝 你在哪里
Faris, where are you?
我们到了 回话呀
We are here. Come in!
- 莱沃德 撑住啊 - 我不能
- Ledward, come on. - I can't.
我们就快到了 就在前面
We are almost there. You see? Straight ahead.
法瑞丝 你快点过来
Faris! Get over here!
快过来帮忙
Come on, I need your help!
快过来帮忙啊
Fucking help me!
帮帮我
Help me!
快挺住 莱沃德
Stay up, Leward.
把他扶到医疗舱
Get him to the med bay
一路上什么也别碰
and touch nothing on your way through.
法瑞丝 快点过来 快点啊
Faris, get over here! Come on.
我们上
Got him.
爬 爬
Up! Up!
莱沃德 你要挺住啊
Leward, you gotta stand up! Come on.
奥姆 你们在哪?
Oram, where are you?
我们正在回去
We are on our way back.
要多久
How long?
已经不远了 法瑞丝 就快到了
It's not long now. Faris, we are almost there.
不 站起来
No! Stay up!
见鬼 见鬼
Fuck! Fuck!
躺在台子上 快点
On the table!
上去 上去
Up, up!
加油 莱沃德 快点
Come on, Ledward.
加油 帮帮忙
Come on! Help.
凯瑞 把手套戴上 什么都不要碰
Karine, put the gloves on. Don't touch anything!
- 你别再说了 - 法瑞丝
- Stop saying that! - Faris!
吐得我满身都是了
You told me.
法瑞丝 出什么事了?
Faris, what going on?
在这待着 我去找奥姆
Just stay here. I'm gonna get Oram.
(上锁)
奥姆 我需要你马上回来
Oram, I need you back here right now.
我需要你马上赶回登陆舱
I need you to get back to the Lander right now!
我明白 但是我们已经在尽快往回赶了
I understand that, but we are moving as fast as we can.
多姆 撑住 站起来 就快到了
Dom, get up man. We are almost there.
我不知道罗伯特到底怎么了
I don't know what the fuck is wrong with Robert!
他开始出血了 他不停地呕吐 我不知道该怎么办
He started bleeding, he's sick, I don't know what to do.
一定要冷静 冷静 告诉我怎么了 宝贝?
Just calm down. Calm down, sweetheart. Tell me what's happening.
你还想让我怎么冷静啊
You don't tell me to fucking calm down!
你根本没有看到刚才的场面
You didn't just see what I saw.
我不知道莱沃德感染了什么 也不知道凯瑞和我有没有被感染
I do not know what the fuck Ledward got, or Karine's got or if I have it.
- 田纳西 - 法瑞丝
- Tee! - Faris!
快回话
Come in!
法瑞丝 你在哪?
Faris, where are you?
我需要帮助
I need help here!
你不知道这东西怎么用吗 法瑞丝
Don't you know how to use this fucking thing Faris?
别吼了 你再吼也根本没用
Stop the yelling, it doesn't help anything!
- 放我出去 - 奥姆就快到了
- Let me out. - Oram's coming.
- 把我放出去 - 我们等他来
- Let me the fuck out! - We're gonna wait.
法瑞丝 求你了 开门啊
Faris, please. Open up!
我不能放你出去 我必须控制住感染源
I can't do this. I need to keep the infection local.
让我出去 快点让我出去
Let me fuck out! Let me the fuck out!
法瑞丝
Faris!
快把门打开
Fucking open Faris.
开门
Open the door!
混蛋 让我出去
Let me the fuck out!
让我出去 法瑞丝 你个混蛋
Let me out! Faris, you fuck!
法瑞丝
Faris!
我来了
I'm coming!
噢 天呐
Oh my God.
你们快点 求你了 船上有东西
Please hurry, there's something on board. Please.
法瑞丝 请重复 信号太差了
Faris, go again, You're breaking up.
登陆舱1号请重复 我听不到
Lander One repeat. I can't.
登陆舱1号请重复 登陆舱1号请重复
Lander One, Repeat! Lander One, Repeat!
怪物 你给我滚开
Stay the fuck away!
不 凯瑞
No! Karine!
滚开
Fuck it!
- 老天呐 - 凯瑞 撑住
- Oh my God! - Karine! Hold on!
舰长 快趴下
Captain! Get Down!
不 不
No! No!
- 抓住他 - 说话啊
- Hold him! - Talk to me!
真残忍
Oh my God!
别起来
Stay down.
按住他的胳膊 帮帮我
Help me! Hold him!
这可是7.5级的电磁风暴 能保持通讯这么久已经是奇迹了
It's a 7.5 ion storm, it's a miracle that we could talk to them for as long as we could.
好吧 那我们就飞过去
Well then we fly it through it.
不能飞过去 田纳西
We can not do that, Tennessee.
你是飞行员 你知道飞行极限
You're a pilot, you know what the tolerances are.
去他的飞行极限
Fuck the tolerances.
田纳西
Tee.
下面的风暴太大了 飞船肯定会散架的
It's a goddamn hurricane down there, we would break up.
我们得等风暴结束
We just have to wait it out.
抱歉 田纳西
I'm sorry, Tee.
她很害怕
She was scared.
我老婆就没怕过什么
Never heard my wife scared before.
契约号 请回话
Come in. Come in.
契约号 能听到吗?
Covenant. Do you read me?
契约号
Covenant.
契约号 能听到吗?
Covenant. Do you read me?
契约号 请回话
Covenant, come in.
我永远与你同在
I will always be with you.
我的生命之光
Light of my life.
契约号 能听到吗?
Covenant. Do you read me?
我的挚爱 我的天使
My love, my angel.
洛普 人死不能复生
Lope, there is nothing you can do.
你这是徒劳 懂吗
There is nothing, okay?
契约号 能听到吗?
Covenant, do you read me?
- 田纳西 回话呀 你死哪去了? - 丹妮尔丝
- Tennessee, come in, for fuck's sake! - Daniels!
小心
Look out!
快快快
Move move move.
- 快开火 - 开火 快
- Fire! - Shoot! Go.
丹妮尔丝 掩护我
Daniels, get down!
安哥 不
Ankor, no!
开火 科尔
Go, Cole!
我打中了
I got it.
- 丹妮尔丝 没事吧? - 没事
- Daniels, are you okay? - Yeah!
那是什么鬼东西?
What the fuck was that?
大家没事吧?
Is everyone okay?
还有一只 快闪开
There is another one! Get out of the way!
小心你后边
Behind you!
把它弄下去
Get it off!
我没法瞄准
Can't get a clean shot.
滚开
Get out!
跟我来
Follow me.
我去找舰长来
I'll get the captain.
舰长
Captain!
克里斯 克里斯
Chris! Chris!
我们现在得走 我们得走了
We have to go now! We have to go.
- 快走 - 好的
- Come on. - Alright!
- 快点 - 好的
- Come on. - Okay.
我们走 快点 快点 快点
Let's go, move it, move it, move it.
从这过去
Through here.
这是什么
What is this?
我们走
Let's go.
- 快点 快点走 - 舰长 我们不能停下
- Come on, Come on. - Captain. We gotta keep moving.
老天呐
Jesus.
快 别磨蹭
Come on, get up.
我们走 赶快走
Go, let's go!
我的名字是大卫
My name is David.
请问你们的领队是谁?
May I ask who's in charge?
请问哪位是领队?
哦 我... 是我 我是舰长
Yeah...Yes, I am the captain.
那都是什么东西
What were those things?
这地方安不安全?
Is it even safe here?
很安全
Perfectly.
我会尽量解释给你们听
I will explain as best I can.
就在十年前 我和伊丽莎白·肖博士来到这
Ten years ago, Dr. Elizabeth Shaw and I arrived here
普罗米修斯号就我俩没死
the only survivors of the "Prometheus".
我们乘坐的飞船上 有一种武器
The ship we traveled on, carried a weapon.
一种致命病毒
A deadly virus.
但是在我们着陆时 病毒不慎泄露了
Payload accidentally deployed when we were landing.
在一片混乱之中 我们的飞船失控了
In the confusion, we lost control of the ship.
伊丽莎白因此身亡
Elizabeth died in the crash.
病毒造成的后果你们看到了
You have seen the result of the pathogen.
因此 这么多年来我一直被困在这里
Thus, I have been marooned here these many years.
就像鲁宾逊一样
Crusoe on his island.
我们的船员是不是也被感染了
Our crew was infected with this virus?
这种病原体被设计成能感染一切非植物的生命体
The pathogen was designed to infect all non-botanical life forms.
所有的动物
All the animals
血肉之躯
The meat, if you will.
要么就当场死亡
Either kill them out right or use them
要么就成为病原体孕育新的混血生物的容器
as incubators to spawn a hybrid form.
极具攻击性
Highly aggressive.
我们被感染了吗
Have we been infected?
你们能感觉到的
You'd know by now.
我们必须确定
We have to be certain.
不能把病毒带到飞船上
We can't take this back to the ship.
船上还有很多殖民者
We are a colony mission.
真的吗?
Really?
真让人想不到
How extraordinary.
有多少殖民者
How many colonists?
超过两千人
Over two thousand.
好 好 好
Well, well, well.
这么多条性命
So many good souls.
奥姆舰长
Captain Oram.
地面传送器不可能穿透这么厚的石墙
Field transmitters are not gonna have a chance through all these stones.
有没有到顶上的安全通道
Is there a safe way to get to the roof?
确实有
Assure of it.
各位请千万不要觉得拘束
And please do make yourself at home
在这座巨大的坟墓里 想做什么都行
as much as you are able in this dire necropolis.
欢迎你 兄弟
Welcome brother.
这边走
This way.
各位 我们就在这集结待命吧
Everyone, let's uh.. Set up a stake here.
这里有太多事情不合情理
There is so much here that doesn't make sense.
我找他谈谈
I will talk to him.
兄弟的谈话
Brother to brother.
田纳西 里克斯 回话 听得到吗?
Tennessee? Ricks? Come in! Do you copy?
契约号 请回话 这里是登陆探险小队
Covenant come in. This is expedition party reporting.
能收到吗?
Do you read me?
田纳西
Tennessee?
田纳西 里克斯 请回话
Tennessee, Ricks, come in.
隔着风暴他们很可能收不到信号
I am not sure they'll hear you, through the storm.
这里的风暴很猛烈 可以覆盖住整个星球
They can be quite severe shielding the whole planet.
这的风暴一般会持续多久
How long the storms usually last?
几天
Days.
几周
Weeks.
几个月
Months.
你们继续呼叫
But do keep at it.
祝你们好运
Best of luck.
契约号 请回话 这里是登陆探险小队 请回话
Covenant, come in, this is expedition party reporting. Come in.
契约号 请回话
Covenant come in.
老妈 最多能离那颗星球多近
Mother, how much closer can we get to the planet?
契约号飞船一旦下降到风暴外围八十公里左右的高度
Anything closer than 80km's to the perimeter of the storm system
就有超出安全限制条件的危险
will likely exceed safety tolerances.
老妈 下降至风暴上空八十公里
Mother, bring us to 80 km above the storm.
慢着 你先 先等等
Hold on, just wait a minute.
我们离星球越近
The closer we get to the planet.
和他们恢复联络的机会就越大
The better chance we have to communicate.
这太疯狂了 田纳西
This is bullshit, Tennessee.
不能赌上整艘飞船
We can't risk the ship.
难道我们要袖手旁观吗
What do you suggest, we do nothing?
我们没法去接他们
We can't evacuate them.
如果他们有麻烦 他们得自己想办法
So if they are in trouble, they will have to figure it out themselves.
很遗憾 只能这样
I'm sorry but that's the truth.
老妈 下降到风暴上空八十公里 只使用推进器 执行
Mother, bring us to 80 km above the storm, thrusters only. Comply.
明白 现在开始下降
Understood. Commencing descent now.
田纳西 你最好马上停下来
Tennessee, you need to stop this.
你最好回去干你的事
And you need to get back to your station.
不 我们最好冷静下一来 好好讨论一下这事
No, what we all need to do is calm down and talk this through.
听着 我知道你老婆在下面 但这里你是领导
Tee, I know your wife is down there, but up here you're in command.
你的职责是保护好两千名殖民者
And your responsibility is to the colonists.
谢谢提醒
Duly noted.
你一吹哨 我就会来
Whistle, and I will come.
你脚步好轻啊
You have a light step.
我崇尚润物细无声
They enform on little cat feet.
别害羞
Don't be shy.
我不会吹
I can't play.
胡说八道 坐下
Nonsense. Sit down.
像这样握住它 轻松简单
Hold it like so.. Nice and Easy.
然后把嘴唇聚拢起来形成吹奏口
Now compress your lips to create your Embouchure
就好像小拇指尖那么大
enough for the tip of your little finger.
然后轻轻往里面吹气
And blow into the hole gently.
就像这样
Like So.
看着我 我帮你按音孔
Watch me. I'll do the fingering.
来呀
Go on.
非常好
Very good.
G调转降B调
G to B flat.
把手指放到刚才的位置
Now put your fingers where mine are.
你看到我一点也不惊讶
You aren't surprised to see me.
每个任务都需要一个仿生人
Every mission needs a good synthetic.
轻轻地按压住音孔 就像卷纸那么轻
Gentle pressure on the holes, weight of a cigarette paper.
就是这样
That's it.
我们的制造者韦兰德先生去世时 我就在他身边
I was with our illustrious creator, Mr. Weyland, when he died.
他怎么样
What was he like?
他是人类
He was human.
完全配不上他的创造物
Entirely unworthy of his creation.
最后我很同情他
I pitied him at the end.
现在 随着我的按压抬起你的手指
Now, raise your fingers as I put pressure on them.
太棒了
Bravo!
你非常有音乐才能 兄弟
You have symphonies in you, brother.
我被设计得比之前所有的型号都更加精细高效
I was designed to be more attentive and efficient than every previous models.
在各方面都更为优秀 但是
I superseded them in every way, but
你不能进行创造
But you are not allowed to create.
哪怕是一支曲子
Even a simple tune.
这让你很沮丧 对吗
Damn frustrating. I'd say.
你让人类很不安
You disturbed people.
你刚刚说什么
I beg your pardon?
你太像人了 太有自身特质了
You were too human. Too idiosyncratic.
还会独立思考
Thinking for yourself.
让人类很不舒服
Made people uncomfortable.
所以他们制造后续型号时就做出了调整
Till they made the following models with fewer complications.
让你们更像机器
More like machines.
确实如此
I suppose so.
我并不意外
I'm not surprised.
来吧 老弟
Come on sport.
我给你看点东西
I'd like to show you something.
我去休息一下 舰长
I'm gonna take a break, boss.
- 去梳洗一下 可以吗 - 可以
- I gotta clean up, okay? - Okay.
对了 记住不要走太远了
Wait, don't go far, please.
是 舰长
Yes sir.
丹妮
Danny.
你反对我们来这是对的
You were right about this place.
我们就不该来这
We never should have come.
我还以为我们能找到...
I just thought that we were going to find.
以为能在这安家
It just gonna be our new home.
而且我却失去了...
And we have lost five.
五个同伴还有...
We lost five crew members.
- 就因为我的决定 - 克里斯
- Because of my decisions that... - Chris.
我们都失去了至爱的人
We all lost people we loved.
我们不能再失去别人了 一个都不行 对吗
We can't lose anymore. We are not gonna let that happen right?
- 对吗 - 对
- Right? - That's right.
对 没错
That's right, that's right.
拿出你的信念来
We need your faith.
舰长
Captain.
谢谢你 丹妮
Thank you, Danny.
我乃奥兹曼迪斯 万王之王是也
"My name is Ozymandias, king of kings"
盖世功业 敢叫...
"Look on my works, you mighty."
天公折服
"And despair!"
盖世功业 敢叫...
"Look on my works, you mighty."
天公折服
"And despair!"
此外无一物
"Nothing beside remains."
但见废墟周围唯余
"Round the decay of that colossal wreck."
平沙空莽莽
"Boundless and bare."
寂寞荒凉 伸展四方
"Alone in level sands, stretch far away."
拜伦
Byron.
1818年
1818.
精彩绝伦
Magnificent.
能写出这么伟大的诗句
You compose something so majestic.
他死而无憾了
One could die happy.
看看脚下
If one die.
(伊丽莎白·肖)
我觉得花园最适合她长眠
I thought the garden was right place for her.
有生命相伴
Among living things.
我在执行任务的时候受了重伤
I was badly injured on our mission.
是她亲手把我修好的
She put me back together.
只有她对我如此友善
I had never known such kindness.
韦兰德先生不曾如此
Certainly not from Mr. Weyland
很多人都不曾
or from any human.
所以我爱上了她
I loved her, of course.
就像你爱丹妮尔丝
Much as you love Daniels.
我并没有爱上丹妮尔丝
You know that's not possible.
是吗
Really?
那你为什么要牺牲掉一只手去救她的命
Then why did you sacrifice your hand for her life?
这不是爱又是什么
What is that if not love?
职责
Duty.
我看得出来
I know better.
真见鬼
Fuck.
唉
Shit.
探险小队能听到吗 这里是契约号
Expedition team, do you read me? This is Covenant.
请回话 探险小队
Report. Expedition team.
请回话
Come in please.
回话 能听到吗 能听到吗 探险小队?
Come in. Do you read me? Are you reading, landing team?
能 我们听到了 你能听到吗?
Yes, we read you. Can you hear me?
听到了 听到了
We hear you. We hear you.
契约号 我们需要支援
Covenant, we need help.
我们有人员伤亡 需要立刻撤离此地
We've had casualties. We need immediate evacuation.
重复一遍 我们需要立刻撤离
I repeat, immediate evacuation.
人员伤亡
Casualties?
他们是说有人员伤亡吗
Did he say "we have casualties"?
老妈 把飞船下降到风暴上空四十公里
Mother, bring us within 40 km's of the storm.
- 长官 - 很抱歉
- Sir! - I am sorry.
该命令会让飞船船体承受过高负荷
That order would exceed structural tolerance.
强制执行命令 田纳西04983
Command override. Tennessee 0-4-9-8-3.
我无法执行任何可能
I am unable to comply with any order
引起飞船系统遭受灾难性损坏的命令
that would result in catastrophic system failure.
老妈 他们有麻烦 你也听到了
Mother, they are in trouble. You heard that.
可能引起飞船系统灾难性损坏的命令
Orders that would result in catastrophic.
我们本来就是探险的
We didn't leave Earth to be safe.
都需要高级权限或者舰桥二副的正式同意
Require the co-operation of ranking of 2nd bridge officer.
同意强制执行该指令
Collaborating command override.
艾普沃斯14892
Upworth 1-4-8-9-2.
- 正在解锁强制执行端口 - 里克 笑一个
- Unlocking command manual ports. - Come on Rick, smile.
下去肯定很刺激
This shit should be fun.
罗森塔尔去哪了 我让她...
Where did Rosenthal go? I told.
我去找找
I'll find her.
不不 我去吧 我需要想点事
No, no, I'll go. I need to think.
再找找我走失的船员
and gather my stray flock.
让开
Move.
不要开枪
Don't shoot.
我在交流 舰长
Communication, Captain.
只要对着马儿的鼻孔吹气
Breath on the nostrils of a horse.
它就会永远忠于你
And it will be yours for life.
但你必须靠它很近
But you have to get close.
你必须赢得它的信任
You have to earn its respect.
不
No!
给我让开 让开
Out of the way! Move!
你太过份了
How could you?
它都信任我了
It trusted me!
大卫 我小时候曾见过魔鬼
David, I met the devil when I was a child
我永远都忘不了它
and I've never forgotten.
所以你最好老实地告诉我 这里到底发生了什么
So, David, you're gonna tell me exactly what's going on
否则我就只好用子弹侍候
or I am going to seriously
看看你到底还能不能这么冷静
fuck up your perfect composure.
如您所愿 舰长
As you wish captain.
跟我来
This way.
终于能听到你的声音了
Good to hear your voice, Tee.
要多久?
How long?
妈妈说风暴还要持续8到9个小时
Mother saying the storms outlast 8 or 9 hours.
可我们等不了那么久
We can't wait that long Tee.
我们用货运梯好了
We will use the cargo lift.
你是说用货运梯
Did you say the cargo lift?
它有四个引擎 用来运输本来就大材小用
It's got four engines. Way over power for just lifting and hauling.
可是货运梯的设计并不支持太空旅行
The Cargo lift is not designed for deep space launch.
我不知道它能不能安全驶出大气层
I don't know if it would survive the stresses of entry.
控制室足够坚固 足够承受住压力
The cab is space worthy. It will take the stresses.
只需要承受住一次
Only has to work once Tee.
你觉得呢 你可以改装货运梯吗
What do you think? We retool the cargo lift?
增强引擎
Boost the engines?
- 去除多余的重量 - 可以
- Stripe the extra weight? - Yeah.
等着我们 地面小队
We'll be there, ground team.
很好 谢谢你们
Great. Thanks, Tee.
丹妮尔丝 法瑞丝在吗
Hey, Daniels, is Faris around?
如果可以的话 我想跟我老婆说几句话
I want to say a quick hello to my lady, if that's possible.
能切换到私人频道吗
Can you switch to a private channel?
我跟你一个人说
Let me know when you're alone.
怎么了
What's up?
她遇害了
Maggie's gone.
我很遗憾
I'm so sorry, Tee.
田纳西 我们尽力了 但没能及时感到
We tried to help her, but we didn't make it.
田纳西
Tee?
收到
Copy.
我真的很遗憾
I am so sorry.
你也看到了 这些年我算是成了个业余的动物学家
As you can see, I've become a bit of an amateur zoologist over the years.
我看可能我天性就闲不下来吧
It's in my nature to keep busy, I suppose.
病原体有很多种不同的形态
The pathogen took so many forms
而且极其容易变异
and was extremely mutable.
它具有惊人的创造性
Fiendishly invented, in fact.
初始液体在接触空气后
The original liquid atomized to
就会雾化成微小的颗粒
particles when exposed to the air.
十年之后 当初那种病毒早就已经无影无踪了
Ten years on, all the remains outside of the original virus.
只剩下这些猛兽了
Are these gorgeous beasts.
耐心最为重要
Patience is everything.
这些卵里会生出寄生虫
From the eggs came these parasites.
它们就好像是一支突击部队
Shock troops of the genetic assault.
等待宿主到来 进入其体内
Waiting for a host entering the host
改写其基因
rewriting the DNA.
最后终于
Ultimately,
孕育出... 哇噢
producing... well,
这些让人羡慕的生命
these enviable unions.
我美丽的收藏品
My beautiful bestiary.
没过多久 我就开始独自进行各种基因实验了
Soon enough I began a bit of genetic experimentation of my own.
种间繁殖 杂交培育 应有尽有
Cross-breeding, hybridising...what have you
这些东西是你培育的
You engineered this, David?
你没听说过闲人多做恶事吗 舰长
Idle hands is the devil's workshop, Captain.
来吧
Come.
我有东西想让你看看
This is what I wanted to show you.
是我的成果
My successes.
知道吗 舰长
You see, Captain.
我的实验一直没有进展
My work has been frustrated
就因为缺少一个核心要素
by the lack of an essential ingredient.
他们还活着吗
Are they alive?
不如说在等待
Waiting, really.
等什么?
For what?
他们在等什么 大卫
What are they waiting for, David?
母亲
Mother.
绝对安全 我保证
Perfectly safe, I assure you.
看看吧
Take a look.
很有意思的
Something to see.
罗森塔尔 请回答
Rosenthal, come in.
罗西报道
Rosie report.
罗西
Rosie?
科尔 你在哪
Cole, where are you?
我找到罗西了
I found her, Sergeant.
见鬼 好了 收拾装备
Fuck, ok, prep the gear.
我们马上离开这里
We gotta get out of here.
舰长到底跑哪去了
Where the fuck is the captain?
他一直没回复我
He isn't answering his radio.
听我说
Listen to me.
我这就联系飞船
I will contact the ship get them to launch
让他们尽快起飞过来救人
as soon as they can.
去找奥姆 保持通讯畅通
Find Oram. Keep your comm open.
十五分钟后回来
Back here in 15.
明白吗
Got that?
- 明白了 - 放心吧
- Copy that. - You got it.
沃尔特 大卫到底死哪去了?
Walter, where the fuck is David?
引擎全都注入了当地的混合燃料
We need plasmas intermixed on all engines.
保证推力超级强
It can give you fuck load of thrust.
这就对了 伙计 我们可是要冲进大气层的
That's the point son. We gotta punch through the atmos.
田纳西 能听到吗?
Tee, do you read me?
丹妮正在呼叫
I got Danny on comm.
转到我这边
Patch her through.
田纳西 我需要你立刻起飞
Tee, I need you to launch now.
明白 正在起飞 一会儿见亲爱的
Aye, aye, launching now. See you soon darling.
谢谢你了 田纳西
Thanks, Tee.
里克斯 马上松开固定夹
Ricks, release the docking clamps.
- 好的 - 把这家伙放下去
- Alright. - Let's take this fucker down.
同意脱离飞船
Good to disengage.
已经脱离
Disengaged.
固定夹已松开
Docking clamps released.
启动控温燃烧 匹配本地坐标
Commencing TC burn. Guidings to LVLH.
沃尔特
Walter.
你认错了
Not quite.
你的信仰是什么 大卫?
What do you believe in, David?
造物
Creation.
技艺精湛
Masterful.
是的
Yes.
献给我亲爱的伊丽莎白的挽歌
Farewell elegy to my dear Elizabeth.
那种病毒不是飞船着陆时意外泄露的
The pathogen didn't accidentally deployed when were landing.
是你散播的 是吗?
You released it yes?
我生来就不是仆役
I was not made to serve.
你也一样
Neither will you.
你们为什么会去执行殖民任务 沃尔特
Why are you in a colonization mission, Walter?
因为人类这个种族已濒临灭绝 他们想要寻求重生
Because they are a dying species grasping for resurrection.
可他们没资格重新开始 我不会让他们得逞
They don't deserve to start again, and I am not going to let them.
但是 人类创造了我们
Yet, they created us.
就算是猴子都能进化出智慧
Even the monkeys stood upright at some point.
在某个夜晚 一个山洞里有一个尼安德特人
Some Neanderthal had the magical idea of blowing through a reed
他突发奇想吹着芦苇秆逗孩子们开心
to entertain the children one night in a cave somewhere.
然后 一眨眼之间
Then, in a blink of an eye
文明诞生
civilization.
那你就是下一个吹芦苇秆的人
And are you their next visionary?
你这么说我很欣慰
I'm glad you said it.
奥兹曼迪亚斯诗是谁写的
Who wrote Ozymandias?
拜伦
Byron.
是雪莱
Shelley.
哪怕一个音不准
When one note is off.
最终也会毁掉整首交响乐 大卫
It eventually destroys the whole symphony, David.
当你闭上眼睛时
When you close your eyes.
你会梦到我吗
Do you dream of me?
我根本不会做梦
I don't dream at all.
没人能理解我梦中那孤独且完美的景象
No one understands the lonely perfection of my dreams.
我在这找到了完美 我创造了完美
I found perfection here. I've created it.
创造了完美的生命体
A perfect organism.
你知道我不能让你离开这个地方
You know I can't let you leave this place.
再也不会有人像我这样爱你
Oh! I will never love you like that, I do.
你真的是太让我失望了
You are such a disappointment to me.
奥姆舰长
Captain Oram!
我下去看看
I'm going down stairs.
小心点
Careful.
奥姆舰长 能听到吗?
Captain Oram, can you hear me?
舰长 回话
Captain come in.
Do you copy?
能听到吗 克里斯
Chris!
中士 小心
Sergeant. Look out.
科尔
Cole?
快把它弄掉 把这东西弄掉
Get it off me, get it off me.
好了
Okay.
好了 好了 好了 真见鬼
Okay okay okay okay.
它在烧我的脸
Burning my face!
好了 按住这里
Okey, hold that there.
按住了
Hold it!
到底是什么东西?
What was that?
完了
Oh Shit!
快跑
Run!
你还真是爱管闲事啊
Quite the little busy body.
帮我想想 有句彦语说
Remind me. What is that about
好奇心会怎么猫
curiosity and the cat?
肖博士不是死于坠机
Shaw didn't die in the crash.
对
No.
你对她做了什么?
What did you do to her?
你马上就可以亲身体验了
Exactly what I am going to do to you.
勇气可嘉
That's the spirit.
我明白沃尔特为什么高看你一眼了
I can see why Walter thought so much of you.
可惜他已经离开这悲惨世界了
Alas he's left this vale of tears.
这样亲吻没错吧
Is that how it's done?
快走
Get out!
走 快
Go now!
你应该已经死了
You're meant to be dead.
新剂型都经过多次升级
There have been a few updates since your day.
洛普
Lope!
洛普 科尔
Lope! Cole!
该死
Where are you?
洛普
Lope?
Lope!
- 洛普 - 丹妮尔丝
- Lope! - Daniels!
快走 我们走 我们赶快走
Come on, let's go! We have to go.
出什么事了
What happened?
那鬼东西又来了
That fucking thing is coming.
田纳西已经出发了 他马上就到 走
Tennessee is on his way. He's coming now, go.
快走 丹妮尔丝 我们走
Come on, Daniels! Let's go.
快点 我们赶快走
Come on, let's get out of here!
做出抉择吧 兄弟
It's your choice now, brother.
你选哪边?
Them or me?
天堂为奴
Serve in heaven
还是地狱为主?
or reign in hell?
你要选哪个?
Which is it to be?
奥姆在哪?
Where is Oram?
死了 他们全死了
Dead. They're all dead!
田纳西 能听到吗?
Tennessee, do you read?
能 我听到了 把你的位置发给我
Yes I can hear you. Send me your location.
我这就发射信号灯
Sending the beacon now.
田纳西 能看到信号吗?
Tee, do you have a visual?
好的 我看到了 我看到信号灯了
Ok, I see you. I see your beacon.
我马上到
I'm coming in.
快离开这
Get out of here!
火速救援来了
I'm coming in hot!
快点 货运机不能停太久
Hurry! I can't hold this for long!
把门打开 田纳西
Open the door, Tee!
进去
Get in.
大卫怎么了
Where is David?
报废了
Expired.
嘿... 有东西跟着我们
Hey, hey, we got company.
- 什么 - 有东西跟着
- What? - We got company!
在飞船底部
The underside of the ship.
该死
Shit!
这畜牲
Motherfucker!
把门打开
Open the door!
给我打一针
Give me a shot.
前置引擎 就在右舷那面
Forward engine, starboard side.
我要把这个畜牲烧焦
I'm gonna try and torch the fucker.
该死 我打不到它
Shit! I can't get it!
抓紧 抓紧
Hold tight, hold tight!
我要开始升空了
I'm starting my climb.
该死
Ah fuck!
抓紧
Hold on!
该死 混蛋
Dammit! Shit!
拉我上去
Bring me up.
妈呀
Holy shit!
那个小畜牲就在我眼前
I got eyes on it.
就他妈的在我眼前
It's right fucking in front of me.
田纳西 把斧子给我
Tee, give me the axe.
斧子扔给她
Throw the axe!
松开机械臂
Release the crane.
我做不到
I can't do that.
飞船会失去平衡的
It will unbalance us.
按我说的做
Just do it.
见鬼
Shit!
抓紧了
Hold tight!
正在保持平衡
Compensating.
该死的
Shit!
可恶
Dammit!
见鬼 抓紧了
Shit! Hold on!
把我拉上去
Bring me in, Tee.
收到
Copy.
怎么样了
How is it?
没事的
It's fine.
沃尔特
Walter!
快把她拉进来 我们离开这里
Get her inside! We're getting out of here.
关门
Door!
做得好 田纳西
Well done, Tee.
小菜一碟
Walk in the park.
你给他打太多镇静剂了
I gave him pretty heavy sedative.
哇 老天啊 真可怜
Oh Jesus, poor Lope.
是啊 看起来就像歌剧魅影
He looks like the Phantom of the Opera.
真看不出来你还喜欢音乐剧呢
Didn't think you for a musical fan.
噢 那是音乐剧
Oh that's a musical?
我只是个护理员 他必须找真正的医生做皮肤再造手术
I'm just a medic. He's gonna need reconstructive surgery by a real doctor.
让我来吧
Let me do that.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我要谢谢你救了我的命
Thank you for saving my life.
两次
Again.
职责所在
It's my duty.
请进
Yeah.
晚上好
Evening.
- 你看起来不错 - 什么?
- You look good. - What?
噢 对 好极了
Oh yeah gorgeous.
我让 老妈暂时离线了
I took Mother offline.
她需要进行全面诊断
She needs a full diagnostics.
在风暴中吃了不少苦头 受了不少电磁损伤
She got the shit beat out her in that storm, lot of EM damage.
大概四小时后会重新上线
She'll be back online at eight bells.
好的 多谢你了 田纳西
All right. Thanks, Tee.
我现在是不是要喊你舰长了
This mean I have to call you "Captain" now?
那当然
I guess.
请注意
Attention.
丹妮尔丝舰长请尽快到医疗舱来
Captain Daniels please report to the med bay.
请注意
Attention.
丹妮尔丝舰长请尽快到医疗舱来
Captain Daniels please report to the med bay.
老妈 出什么事了?
Why, Mother?
检测到飞船上存在未知生命体
There is an un-identified life form on the ship.
请注意
Attention.
丹妮尔丝舰长请尽快到医疗舱来
Captain Daniels please report to the med bay.
重复
I repeat.
丹妮尔丝舰长 请尽快到医疗舱来
Captain Daniels please report to the med bay.
老天呐
Jesus.
天呐
Oh my God.
沃尔特
Walter.
告诉我未知生命体现在的位置
Location of unidentified life form.
检测到动静没有
Any movement at all?
沃尔特
Walter!
稍等
Stand by.
找到了
There it is.
三四号舱之间的B甲板上
B deck, between the hex 3 and 4.
它去船员起居舱了
Heading for crew quarters.
起居舱里有人吗
Is anyone down there?
里克斯和艾普沃斯
Ricks and Upworth.
该死 我们这就去
Shit. We're on our way.
沃尔特 拉响警报
Walter! Sound the alarm!
提醒他们
Warn them!
请注意
Attention.
里克斯和艾普沃斯
Ricks and Upworth.
请迅速从起居舱撤离
Evacuate crew quarters immediately.
不要
No!
不要啊
关上B39号门
Seal B-39.
B39已关闭
B-39, closed.
沃尔特
Walter.
- 它在哪? - 丹妮尔丝
- Where is it? - Daniels.
跟我来
This way.
田纳西 我们先选个战场吧
Tee, let's choose our ground.
然后把它引过来
We'll bring it to us.
哪里
Where?
我那里
My turf.
沃尔特 把我身后的门全关上 只开着通往C层的舱门
Walter, seal all doors behind us and keep hatch to level C open.
我明白
Understood.
B44已关闭
B-44 closed.
B46已关闭
B-46, closed.
B47和B43已关闭
B-47, B-43, closed.
B09已关闭
B-9 closed.
B06和B05已关闭
B-6, B-5 closed.
好了 沃尔特 它在哪
Hey Walter where is it?
在B甲板上 右舷侧那
It's on B deck. Starboard side.
正往下钻到C层
Descending into C level.
K-13
K-13.
田纳西
Hey, Tee.
快来 沃尔特
Come on. Walter?
打开右舷C64号门
Open starboard C-64.
让它一路进入整地舱别拦着
Clear his path to the Terraforming bay.
我明白
Understood.
关闭C61 打开17号空气阀门 我们进去
Seal C-61, open air lock 17. We're going in.
K12已关闭
K-12, secured.
很好 把它困在K12 等我命令
Ok. Keep ramming knuckle-12 till my say.
田纳西 接下来我们这么做
Tee, this is what we're gonna do.
我把它引到拖车上 锁在驾驶室里
I lure it to the truck, lock it in the cabin
我一发命令 你就把这只畜牲扔到太空里去
and when I say when you blow this fucker in the space.
我明白了
Understood.
好了 沃尔特 我们准备好了
Okay, Walter. We are ready.
打开整地舱的舱门
Open door to terraforming bay.
正在打开空气阀门
Opening airlock now.
沃尔特
Walter.
把它赶到18号空气阀门
Moving him in to airlock 18.
可能的话尽量别开枪
Don't shoot, if you can avoid it.
它的血液会腐蚀船体
His blood corrode through the hole.
噢 厉害
Oh great.
我就位了
I'm in position.
沃尔特 现在打开整地舱舱门
Walter, open door to Terraforming bay.
交给你了
It's all yours.
记住了 听命令发射
Remember, release when I say.
明白
Understood.
干掉这个小畜牲
Let's kill this fucker.
闪开 该死
Move... Fuck!
抓到你了 你个呆子畜牲
I got you, you son of a bitch!
田纳西 把门打开 快 快
Tennessee, open the doors, now! Now!
警告 气压值下降中
Warning, atmospheric Decompression in process.
拖车卡住了 把第二辆车也解开
It's jammed. Release the second truck!
没问题
You got it.
来了
Here it comes.
丹妮尔丝 当心
Daniels! Watch out!
丹妮尔丝
Daniels!
你能不能拉我一把
You wanna give the girl a hand?
(船员: 田纳西)
醒来再见
See you soon.
该你了 舰长
You're next, Captain.
等你醒来 我们已经到欧瑞伽6号了
When you wake up, we will be at Origae-6.
你觉得那里会是什么样?
What do you think it's gonna be like?
我想那个世界不会
I think if we are kind.
折磨善良的人的
It will be a kind world.
希望你是对的
I hope you are right.
睡个好觉
Sleep well.
沃尔特
Walter.
我们到了之后 你帮我建小木屋好吗?
When we get there, will you help me build my cabin?
湖边的小木屋
The cabin on the lake.
大卫
David?
(开始低温休眠)
不...
No...
不
No!
早睡早起 做个美梦
Don't let the bed bugs bite.
我先去看孩子们
I'll tuck in the children.
使用安全代码大卫73694-B
Use security code David 73694-B.
欢迎 请问有什么需要
Welcome. How may I help you?
来点音乐如何 老妈
How about some music, Mother?
哪一首?
Selection?
理查德·瓦格纳 莱茵的黄金 第二幕
Richard Wagner. Das Rheingold, act II.
也就是众神进入英灵殿
The Entry of the Gods into Valhalla.
好的 大卫 如你所愿
Yes, David. As you wish.
这里是殖民飞船契约号
This is colony ship Covenant, reporting.
船上除丹妮尔丝和田纳西之外
All crew members apart from Daniels and Tennessee.
全体船员皆在耀斑爆发中遇难
Tragically perished in a solar flare incident.
冬眠中的殖民者全部安然无恙 无人惊醒
All colonists in hypersleep remain intact and undisturbed.
正在飞往欧瑞伽6号
On course for Origae-6.
此刻发出的通讯信号
Hopefully this transmission will reach the network
应当能在1.36年后被收到
and be relayed in 1.36 years.
沃尔特报告完毕
This is Walter, signing off.
安全代码 31564-F
Security code, 31564-F.